

# Md. Nahidul Islam Opu

- ■ opu.nahidul@gmail.com
  - nahidul-opu.github.io
  - github | in linkedin

### **SUMMARY**

I am a student and a machine learning enthusiast. I have 2+ years of experience in game development using UnityEngine. I also have 2+ years of experience in research on machine learning. I am also interested in backend development. I am a quick learner who loves problem solving.

#### SKILLS \_

- Proficient in Python, C#, C++
- Proficient in HTML, MySQL
- · Proficient in Git
- Proficient in Latex
- Proficient in Python Libraries: Pandas, Keras, Numpy etc
- OOP & Functional Programming
- Game Development (Unity Engine)

- · Machine Learning and Deep Learning
- Good understanding of data structure & algorithms
- Web Development
- Competitive programming: Codeforces (371)
- Familiar with Java, PHP, C, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, Django, Android Studio

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Research Experience**

Working on Artificial Intelligence

- ·Bangla handwritten character recognition using CNN
- Augmented reality with machine learning
- •Covid-19 detection from chest X-ray using andorid application
- •Age and gender prediction using CNN. Published on IEEE Xplore

### **Arcade Studios**

Nov 2019 - July 2020

Intern Software Engineer

### **Arcade Studios**

July 2020 - Present

Junior Software Engineer (Part-time)

- Working as a game developer using Unity Engine
- Worked on Integration of Machine Learning into Game development

#### **EDUCATION**

# Chittagong University of Engineering and Technology

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

2017-Present

- Current CGPA: 3.5 (Up untill 5th semester)
- Working on Machine learning for undergraduate thesis

# Govt. Ananda Mohan College, Mymensingh

2014-2016

H.S.C

• GPA: 5.00

# Mymensingh Zilla School, Mymensingh

2006-2014

S.S.C

• GPA: 5.00

### **SOFTWARE PROJECTS**

### **Learn to Write**

Android application to teach handwriting to kids

Using Unity3D, C#, Python and ML Libraries

### MediCare

An Andorid app to find doctor, hospital, ambulance with map

·Using Java, PHP, MySQL, Google Map API

### **FilesHere**

A file sharing website

Using PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL

### Flower Classifier

An Andorid app to classify several types of flowers

- Using Unit3D, C#, Python and ML libraries
- Deployed on heroku using flask

### File Locker

File vault with face recognition

Using Python and ML Libraries

## **Machine Learning Algorithms**

Pure Python implementation of several ML algorithms. Available in Github

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars.